Finding Aid for the George P. Johnson Negro Film Collection LSC.1042
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Personal papers, photographs, magazines, books, and files of Lincoln Motion Picture Company
  - General Files
    - JFK assassination. (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Opposition houses - mailing list., May 1921 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Los Angeles Housing Authority - receipts. (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Film producers (early) with Negro actors. (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Amistad Research Center News (New Orleans, )., September 1975 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Abajian, James de T. - correspondence, 1971. (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Larry Edmund's Bookshop - catalogues. (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - Durham, Phillip - correspondence, 1968. (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Kagan, Norman - correspondence, 1970-1971. (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Moss, Carlton - Miscellaneous information. (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - Brooks, Clarence - lists of information. (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - The Art of Coloring Photographs. (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - WEB DuBois - letter to Noble Johnson ()., 1918; Original and 2 copies. (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - Johnson, Noble - non-photo material. (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - By Right of Birth - film synopsis. (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Law of Nature - film synopsis. (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - A Man's Full Duty - film synopsis. (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Address list. (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - papers in vault., 1970 (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - Movie stars' real names. (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - Integration - article and clippings. (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Funeral register. (Box 52, Folder 42)
    - Hersholt, Jean - Miscellaneous information. (Box 52, Folder 43)
    - U.S. Official Postal Guide (covers only, )., 1929-1930 (Box 52, Folder 44)
    - Address book. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - DeMille, Cecil B. - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Bette - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Cinema magazine - articles - lists. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Bush, Peggy - letters to, 1970-1972. (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - American Film Institute Report., May 1971 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Hudson, Rock - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Harlow, Jean - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Jones, James Earl - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Greeley, Aurora - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Gable, Clark and Kay - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Films in Review - lists. (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Johnson, Van - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Jones, Phil - letters to []., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Keeler, Ruby - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Movie star home addresses - lists. (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Kramer, Stanley - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Johnson, George P. - Miscellaneous. (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Jones, Chester - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Colbert, Claudette - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Cinema - carbon. (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Jones, Quincy - Miscellaneous information. (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Noble Johnson material - lists - biographies - Miscellaneous. (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - Juanita (song) - sheet music. (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - financial statements, 1921. (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - Negro film productions - lists. (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - Monumental Picture Corporation (Washington, D.C.) - letter, 1920. (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - Statements and receipts for the Lincoln Motion Picture Company showings, 1917-1918. (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Stock certificates - G.P. Johnson, Thomas Smith, Harry A. Gant, May 1922. (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - Negro and white movie corporations - lists - Miscellaneous. (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - Jackson, James A. - editorial department - Billboard Putnam Building (New York). (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - Contract - Noble Johnson and Lincoln Motion Picture Company., June 1916 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Contract - Noble Johnson and Lincoln Motion Picture Company., April 1919 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - George Johnson's visits w/Robert Levy, Emmet J. Smith (Assistant Secretary of War) and Ernest Atwell. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - G.P. Johnson's collection of Negro motion picture material - lists. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Tony Langston - Chicago Defender - letters, 1916. (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Early Negro films and actors. (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Freeman - National Illustrated Colored Newspaper (Indianapolis, Indiana). (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Land title, January 1906. (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Negro writers and their work - list. (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Publications on Negroes and film - lists. (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Magazine - Western Whittlings - vol.1 no.1 (Los Angeles: )., June 1928 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Renie Atlas of Los Angeles. (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Negro Year Book, 1925-1926. (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - UCLA oral history program - with pasted articles inside - letter. (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - To be done. (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Negro Digest., May 1944. (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Rare Negro magazines - list. (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Rent checks and receipts. (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Negroes in film, 1972. (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Prices paid for postage stamps - lists. (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - Williamson, Fred - Miscellaneous information. (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - St. Jacques, Raymond - Miscellaneous information. (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Wilson, Clifford - correspondence, 1971-1972. (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - Williams, Billy Dee - Miscellaneous information. (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - Sentinal newspaper - article () re blacks in California., n.d. (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - 10th U.S. Cavalry - description. (Box 54, Folder 26)
    - G. Johnson - notes. (Box 54, Folder 27)
    - Noble Johnson and Harry Gant - information - with photo. (Box 54, Folder 28)
    - Latest addresses that I have - lists, 1958-1973. (Box 54, Folder 29)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - audit., January 1918 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - Shomberg collection - general information. (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Berry Auction Company - advertisements - appraisals., April 1982 (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - UCLA University Library. (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - Sobel, Henry D. - business card. (Box 54, Folder 34)
    - A sample of my 4x6 files of evelopes from A-G, containing names of films, dates, producers, directors, actors (total 568 A-G). (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - Lithograph posters and photos (stills) - list. (Box 54, Folder 36)
    - Freeman, Virgil and Pearl - correspondence. (Box 54, Folder 37)
    - AFI News, 1973-1974. (Box 54, Folder 38)
    - Appomatox Country Club - advertisement. (Box 54, Folder 39)
    - Universal Kinetis (New York) - letter., 1972 (Box 54, Folder 40)
    - By Right of Birth - advertisements. (Box 54, Folder 41)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - advertisements - general. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - early papers (minutes, etc., )., 1916-1920 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Lists of my film books and magazines. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - The Tulsa Guide [Tulsa, Indian Territory]., 1906 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Trooper of Troop K - advertisements. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - commendations. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Contract - Updike and Lincoln Motion Picture Company - 1921. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Corporation papers - Lincoln Motion Picture Company. (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - A Man's Duty - Trinity Auditorium - advertisements, articles., 24 January 1921 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Lincoln film bookings, contracts, telegrams, theatres, French pictorial (missing), letters. (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - American Film Institute. (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Kennedy, John F. - articles. (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Motion Picture Literature no.10 (copy only). (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Film stencil. (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Stencil and copy - Motion Picture Literature no.9. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Stencil and copy - Motion Picture Literature no.11. (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Presidents and prominent Negroes. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Van Peebles, Melvin - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Negro film productions - lists. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Hepburn, Audrey - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Chaplin, Charlie - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Day, Doris - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - X-Mas - cards sent and received., 1971 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Pickett, Bill - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Crawford, Joan - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Book of actors with movies - pasted in calendar. (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Negro films - articles. (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Films in which Noble Johnson appeared. (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Kennedy, Robert F. - Miscellaneous information. (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Franklin, Wendell - The Bus is Coming. (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - articles. (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Trooper of Troop K and A Man's Duty - movie ad. (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Black movie boom - list. (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Films in which Negroes appear - list. (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Our Gang - articles. (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1917-1976. (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Personal. (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Pacific Coast News Bureau - also Roster of Negro Press - articles pasted in photo album., 1923-1926 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Maps - pasted in a Baash-Ross Tool Company book. (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Magazines
    - Lists. (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Jet magazine - lists. (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Lists - pasted in ledger. (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Conte-Cal., February 1963 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Books and magazines. (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Billboard magazine - lists. (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - American Life., June 1926 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Hue Magazine - list. (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Cinema Magazine - lists. (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Films in Review - lists. (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Competitor Magazine (Pittsburg: )., December 1917 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Cinema Magazine - list. (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - City Magazine., Winter 1971 (Box 57, Folder 23)
    - Negro magazines - lists. (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Printing blocks [no compromise box]. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Books about film [carton]. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Glass slides - 2 song slides (for unidentified song) - 5 Coming attractions slides for A Man's Duty [shoebox]. (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous publications [flatbox]. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous publications [flatbox]. (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Advertisements [v.p., ] [flatbox]., v.d. (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Oversize articles and advertisements [large flatbox]. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Photographs and Negatives
    - Brooks, Clarence - photo and other material. (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Company - members of the board. (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Photo albums: Street Scenes - Elizabeth Johnson. (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Negatives - travel photos, 1960. (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - 4 negatives: no.5878-C-752 [color] Lottie sitting holding Sandy - Lottie sitting in patio - 2 others., January 23, 1961 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - George and Lottie in Aaron's patio and backyard, 1962. (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - 2 negatives: Rose and George - Easter 1928., April 1928 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Negatives - Rose on top Dunbar Hotel, 1928. (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Negatives - Pacific Ocean ()., June 1929 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Negatives - Tia Juana ()., May 1929 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Cemetary ()., May 1928 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Santa Monica, - Castle del Mar ()., 1928 May 1930 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - San Diego ()., May 1929 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Photos - Johnson, Rose. (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Negatives - Johnson's daughter ()., August 1941 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous photos. (Box 60, Folder 17-18)
    - Miscellaneous negatives. (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Photos - Baldwin Hills Dam break ()., February 1964 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Photos - unbound album - Virgil C. Johnson. (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Photo - F. Buell's Real Estate office - Tulsa, Indian Territory. (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Photos - Pickens, Albertine. (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - Photos - Law of Nature. (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Photo album: Photographs - Lottie. (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Photo album: Photographs. (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, Noble. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Negative stills - By Right of Birth. (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Smith, James. (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Photos - Realization. (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Photos - Within Our Gates (Oscar Micheaux film) - starring Evelyn Preer. (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Photos - King, Webb. (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Photos - Thompson, Anita. (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Photos - A Man's Duty. (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Photos - By Right of Birth. (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Photos - Bronze Buckaroo. (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Photos - Harlem Rides the Range. (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Photos - Gunsaulus Mystery. (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Photos - Trooper of Troop K. (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Photos - Pickens, Albertine - Law of Nature. (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Photos - Buelah Hall. (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Photographs, Scrapbook (George's relatives), Lobby Cards, v.d. (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Scope and Content
      Includes lobby cards for:
      By Right of Birth Dolly's Vacation Gunsaulus Mystery Jazz Hounds Little Diplomat Modern Cain Within Our Gates
  - Stamps
    - General. (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - First Flights - Zepplins - parcel post stamps - Lindbergh material. (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Lists. (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Air Mail stamps - history. (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - New corrected buyer's prices, 1965. (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Stamps I have (typed lists). (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Articles. (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Literature. (Box 57, Folder 10)
- Posters
  - Flying Ace - Norman Studios presentation. (Box 71)
    (not on microfilm).
  - A Man's Duty - Lincoln Motion Picture Company. With Clarence Brooks., (2 items). (Box 71)
  - Black Gold - Norman Studios. (Box 71)
  - Playbill. Loring Theatre, Riverside, California. Advertisement for Negro vaudeville and motion pictures. (Box 71)
  - The Trooper of Troop K - Lincoln Motion Picture Company. With Noble M. Johnson. (Box 71)
  - Crimson Skull - Norman Film Manufacturing Company. (Box 71)
  - The Law of Nature - Lincoln Motion Picture Company. With Noble M. Johnson, Albertine Pickens, Clarence A. Brooks. (Box 71)
  - The Green Eyed Monster - Norman Film Manufacturing Company. (Box 71)
  - Injustice - Democracy Film Corporation (3 copies). (Box 71)
  - The Sport of the Gods - Reol Productions. (Box 71)
  - By Right of Birth - Lincoln Motion Picture Company. With Clarence Books and Anita Thompson. (Box 71)
  - Zircon Advertisement for film by Norman Film Manufacturing. (Box 71)